<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Alexohneander</title>
    <link>https://alexohneander.de/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Alexohneander</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 19:20:27 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alexohneander.de/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baremetal CNI Setup with Cilium</title>
      <link>https://alexohneander.de/posts/baremetal-cni-setup-with-cilium/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 19:20:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexohneander.de/posts/baremetal-cni-setup-with-cilium/</guid>
      <description>In a freshly set up Kubernetes cluster, we need a so-called CNI. This CNI is not always present after installation.
What is a Container Network Interface (CNI)? CNI is a network framework that allows the dynamic configuration of networking resources through a group of Go-written specifications and libraries. The specification mentioned for the plugin outlines an interface that would configure the network, provisioning the IP addresses, and mantain multi-host connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site to Site VPN for Google Kubernetes Engine</title>
      <link>https://alexohneander.de/posts/site-to-site-vpn-for-google-kubernetes-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 19:20:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexohneander.de/posts/site-to-site-vpn-for-google-kubernetes-engine/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial I will try to explain you briefly and concisely how you can set up a site-to-site VPN for the Google Cloud Network.
Prerequisites We need 2 virtual machines. The first one on the side of our office and the other one on the side of Google.
Setup OpenVPN Clients Site-to-Site Client Office Side We need to install OpenVPN, we do it as follows:
apt install openvpn -y After that we add our OpenVPN configuration under this path /etc/openvpn/s2s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup MySQL Databases in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://alexohneander.de/posts/backup-mysql-databases-in-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 19:20:27 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexohneander.de/posts/backup-mysql-databases-in-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will show you how to create a MySQL server backup using Kubernetes CronJobs.
In our case, we do not have a managed MySQL server. But we want to backup it to our NAS, so that we have a backup in case of emergency. For this we first build a container that can execute our tasks, because we will certainly need several tasks to backup our cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
